Guide to the Leo L. Ledwich Papers
Special Collections, University of Washington Libraries
Leo L. Ledwich papers
1925-1982
University of Washington Libraries Special Collections Box 352900 Seattle, WA 98195-2900
4061
Ledwich, Leo L.
.63 cu. ft. (2 boxes)
Papers of a dispute within the Retail Clerks International Protective Association, Local 174, 1937 collected by Secretary-Treasurer of the association
In 1937 Leo Ledwich was Secretary-Treasurer of Retail Clerks International Protective Association, Local 174, in Seattle and a vice president of the Retail Clerks International Protective Association. In that year there was a dispute between a number of locals, organized under the name of New Era Committee, and a faction within the International.
Arranged into 2 accessions:
Accession no. 4061-001, Leo L. Ledwich papers, 1925-1937
Accession no. 4061-002, Leo L. Ledwich papers, 1927-1982 (bulk 1930-1948)
Correspondence, minutes, report, petition, financial records, photograph, newsclippings and ephemera created and collected by Leo Ledwich on his career as an officer in the Seattle local of the Retail Clerks International Protective Assocaition, Local 174 (later RCIPA Local 1001) and as an officer in the Retail Clerks International Union.
Open to all users.
Ledwich, Leo L.$vArchives; Coulter, C. C.; Labor Archives of Washington (University of Washington); Retail Clerks International Protective Association. New Era Committee; Washington State Federation of Labor; Retail Clerks International Protective Association; Retail Clerks International Protective Association. Local 174; Retail Clerks International Protective Association. Local 568
Personal Papers/Corporate Records; Labor History; Labor Unions; Retail Trade; Washington (State); Seattle; Photographs
- Leo L. Ledwich papers, 1925-1937; 4061-001; 0.42 cubic feet 1 box
  Arranged by subject.
  Correspondence, minutes, report, petition, financial records and photograph, 1925-1937, concerning a dispute within the Retail Clerks International Protective Association and concerning Local 174 of the RCIPSA, in Seattle. Also includes an unpublished paper on Ledwich by David Boughton, ca. 1980s.
  Some material is photocopies.
  Open to all users.
  Donated by Thomas M. Cox, August 22, 1990.
  - Retail Clerks International Protective Association
    - Incoming Letters, 1937 (Box-folder 1/1)
    - Outgoing Letters, 1931-37 (Box-folder 1/2)
    - Interorganizational Correspondence, 1931-37 (Box-folder 1/3)
    - Minutes, 1937 (Box-folder 1/4)
    - Report, 1937 (Box-folder 1/5)
    - Financial Records, 1929-37 (Box-folder 1/6)
    - Articles Of Agreement, undated (Box-folder 1/7)
    - Photograph, 1937 (Box-folder 1/8)
  - Retail Clerks International Protective Association. Local 174 (seattle)
    - Incoming Letters
      - Retail Clerks International Protective Association, 1926-37 (Box-folder 1/9)
      - Washington State Federation of Labor, 1926-30 (Box-folder 1/10)
      - Miscellaneous A-Z, 1926-28 (Box-folder 1/11)
    - Outgoing Letters, 1925-37 (Box-folder 1/12)
    - General Correspondence (incl. Retail Clerks International Protective Association), 1937 (Box-folder 1/13)
    - Report, 1937 (Box-folder 1/14)
    - Petitions, undated (Box-folder 1/15)
    - Note, undated (Box-folder 1/16)
  - Retail Clerks International Protective Association. Local 568 (seattle), 1931 (Box-folder 1/17)
  - Personal Papers
    - Outgoing Letter, 1928 (Box-folder 1/18)
    - Writing--"the Ledwich Papers" By David Broughton, undated (Box-folder 1/19)
    - Membership Book--communist Party Of The USA (for Jules Kane), 1936 (Box-folder 1/20)
    - Court Paper, 1936 (Box-folder 1/21)
    - Clippings, 1937, 1982 (Box-folder 1/22)
- Leo L. Ledwich papers, 1927-1982; 1930-1948; 4061-002; 0.21 cubic feet 1 box
  Arranged as received.
  Correspondence, newsclippings, ephemera created and collected by Leo Ledwich on his career as an officer in the Seattle local of the Retail Clerks International Protective Assocaition, Local 174 (later RCIPA Local 1001), and as an officer in the Retail Clerks International Union.
  Donated by Ross Rieder, November 13, 2011.